Guide to the Douglas C. Engelbart Papers M0638
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- Series 5. Accession 1991-191
  - Subseries 5.4 Computer Binders, Papers, Notes, Etc.
    - Computer Binders Standard Proposals, April 1977 (Box 68, Folder 1)
    - Computer Binders OP Listings, April 16, 1972 (Box 68, Folder 2)
    - Computer Binders COM (Box 68, Folder 3)
    - Computer Binders PDP-10 Output Processor Listings (Box 68, Folder 4)
    - Computer Binders Documentation PDP-10 Output Processor (Box 68, Folder 5)
    - Computer Binders Calculator (Box 68, Folder 6)
    - Computer Binders Document Compiler (9624) Also Contains Comments WHP-9625 WLB-9626 (Box 68, Folder 7)
    - Computer Binders Portrayal Generator-Needs and Possibilities (Box 68, Folder 8)
    - Computer Binders MPS (Box 68, Folder 9)
    - Computer Binders OP, Listings, February 7, 1973 (Box 68, Folder 10)
    - Executive Manual (rev), February 4, 1971 (Box 69, Folder 1)
    - Output Processor Upgrade InforMation, December 1972 (Box 69, Folder 2)
    - Computer Papers Users Guide to the Jovial Debugger (Box 70, Folder 1)
    - Computer Papers Document Production (Box 70, Folder 2)
    - Computer Papers NLS-8 Glossary (Box 70, Folder 3)
    - Computer Papers Publish Subsystem (Box 70, Folder 4)
    - Computer Papers Template Subsystem (Box 70, Folder 5)
    - Computer Papers NLS User Guide (Box 70, Folder 6)
    - Computer Papers Retrieve Subsystem (Box 70, Folder 7)
    - Computer Papers PSS subsystems (Box 70, Folder 8)
    - Computer Papers Minseq Subsystems (Box 70, Folder 9)
    - Computer Papers MRAO Writing (Box 70, Folder 10)
    - Computer Papers On-line System Guide (Box 70, Folder 11)
    - Computer Papers NrC Team Interaction (Box 70, Folder 12)
    - Computer Papers SMalltalk-80 Papers (Box 70, Folder 13)
    - Computer Papers Query 3 (Box 70, Folder 14)
    - Computer Papers On-line Programmers (Box 70, Folder 15)
    - Computer Papers Augmented Knowledge Workshop (Box 70, Folder 16)
    - Computer Papers Command Metalanguage System (Box 70, Folder 17)
    - Computer Papers DPS Version (Box 71, Folder 1)
    - Computer Papers New File SysteM (Box 71, Folder 2)
    - Computer Papers L10 Documentation (Box 71, Folder 3)
    - Computer Papers Output Processor Users Guide (Box 72, Folder 3)
    - Computer Papers Intro to Augment (Box 72, Folder 4)
    - Computer Papers Table Lesson (Box 72, Folder 5)
    - Computer Papers Intro to Textbook (Box 72, Folder 6)
    - Computer Papers Log-in TYmnet (Box 72, Folder 7)
    - Computer Papers Command Sequences (Box 72, Folder 8)
    - Computer Papers Operator Procedures (Box 72, Folder 9)
    - Computer Papers Operator Procedures (Box 73, Folder 1)
    - Computer Papers Tutor Formatting (Box 73, Folder 2)
    - Computer Papers On-line Team EnvironMent (Box 73, Folder 3)
    - Computer Papers OP Users Guide (Box 73, Folder 4)
    - Computer Papers Stanford Proposal (Box 73, Folder 5)
    - System Control Programming (Box 74, Folder 6)
    - SRI Originals (Box 75, Folder 1)
    - Papers, Projects, and Reports (Box 75, Folder 2)
    - Forms, Reports, and Papers Binders (Box 76, Folder 1)
    - Papers on Texts (Box 76, Folder 2)
    - Help Query Binder, October 1973 (Box 76, Folder 3)
    - Paper on Document Production and Control Systems, March 1977 (Box 76, Folder 4)
    - The Augment Engine Paper (Box 76, Folder 5)
    - NLS9 FE A-D Study on Feasibility of Software Certification, January 1978 (Box 76, Folder 7)
    - NLS9 FE E-Z Study on Feasibility of Software Certification, April 1977 (Box 76, Folder 8)
    - NLS9 FE SYSGD Library Study on Feasibility of Software Certification, April 1977 (Box 76, Folder 9)
    - Report on Design of Automated Text Handling System, August 1974 (Box 77, Folder 1)
    - Other Systems (Box 77, Folder 2)
    - CCA (Box 77, Folder 3)
    - Notes (Box 77, Folder 4)
    - Various Proposals on Subsystems, CML, Standards, Graphics, Surveys (Box 77, Folder 5)
    - Text Papers (Box 77, Folder 6)
    - NLS User Training Guide, March 1978 (Box 78, Folder 1)
    - TNLS Calculator User's Guide, June 1973 (Box 78, Folder 2)
    - On-Line TeaM Environment Guides, June 1972 (Box 78, Folder 3)
    - Reports Human Intellect (Box 78, Folder 4)
    - Reports Network Info (Box 78, Folder 5)
    - Reports Procedure Call Protocol, January 1975 (Box 78, Folder 6)
    - Reports Knowledge-Worker Teams, October 1981 (Box 78, Folder 7)
    - Reports Computer Research, April 1972-April 1973 (Box 78, Folder 8)
    - Reports Timesharing Systems (Box 78, Folder 9)
    - Reports Research Proposals (Box 78, Folder 10)
    - Reports Document Production and Control Systems, March 1977 (Box 79, Folder 1)
    - Reports Software, January 1975 (Box 79, Folder 2)
    - Reports Knowledge Workshop, January 1976 (Box 79, Folder 3)
    - Reports Computer Research (Box 79, Folder 4)
    - Reports NLS User Training Guide (Box 79, Folder 5)
    - Reports Editorial Processing (Box 79, Folder 6)
    - Reports Transmission Specification, July 1976 (Box 80, Folder 1)
    - Reports Waste Proposal, August 1977 (Box 80, Folder 2)
    - Reports Human Intellect, February 1969 (Box 80, Folder 3)
    - Reports Computer Info, April 1972 (Box 80, Folder 4)
    - Reports Graphics, June 1976 (Box 80, Folder 5)
    - Reports Computer Proposals, 1978-1980 (Box 81, Folder 1)
    - Computer Notes (Box 83, Folder 1)
    - Augment Search Research Guide (Box 83, Folder 2)
    - Programmer Notes (Box 83, Folder 3)
    - Content Analyzer Guide (Box 83, Folder 4)
    - Computer Notes (Box 83, Folder 5)
    - Computer Notes Research Projects (Box 84, Folder 1)
    - Computer Notes Systems Guides (Box 84, Folder 2)
    - Computer Notes (odd-shaped papers) (Box 85)
    - Designs in Progress (Box 86, Folder 1)
    - Output Processor (Box 86, Folder 2)
    - Augment Subsystem (Box 86, Folder 3)
    - Department of Defense Study (Box 86, Folder 4)
    - Time Cost Subsystem, 1980 (Box 86, Folder 5)
    - Publication Catalogue Copies (Box 86, Folder 6)
    - General Writings, October 1979 (Box 87)
    - 1980 Publications (Box 87)
    - Catalog Copies (Box 87)
    - Augment System, 1979 (Box 87)
    - Proposals, 1980 (Box 87)
    - Symposium on Advanced Office (Box 87)
    - Automation (Box 87)
    - Computer Papers (Box 87)
    - Computer Papers (Box 88)
    - Computer Papers (Box 89, Folder 1)
    - Binders DCE Office Query 3, March 1977 (Box 89, Folder 2)
    - Binders DCE Office FWIP Record, 1978-1979 (Box 89, Folder 3)
    - Binders DCE Office CM Refs, 1979 (Box 89, Folder 4)
    - Binders DCE Office Prod-Spec, 1979 (Box 89, Folder 5)
    - Binders DCE Office FWIP Working Notes, 1979 (Box 89, Folder 6)
    - Computer Papers (Box 90, Folder 1)
    - Automatic Programming, 1972 (Box 90, Folder 7)
    - User Programs, 1973 (Box 90, Folder 8)
    - Non-NLS Documentation, 1976 (Box 90, Folder 9)
    - Applications Descriptions, 1978 (Box 91, Folder 1)
    - Planning, 1982 (Box 91, Folder 2)
    - Com Product File, June 1972 (Box 91, Folder 3)
    - Corr-hypen, 1981 (Box 91, Folder 4)
    - Weyer Project System, 1977 (Box 91, Folder 5)
    - Computer Papers (Box 91, Folder 6)
    - Computer Papers (Box 92)
    - Computer Papers (Box 93)
    - Computer Papers (Box 94, Folder 1)
    - Project Files 1868-3803, 1974 (Box 94, Folder 2)
    - Users Manual, 1974 (Box 94, Folder 3)
    - Project Files 4042-4395, 1975 (Box 94, Folder 4)
    - Project Files 4612-4857, 1976 (Box 94, Folder 5)
    - Insight Reports, 1981-1982 (Box 95, Folder 1)
    - SRI International Reports, 1982 (Box 95, Folder 2)
    - Computer Papers (Box 95, Folder 3)
    - Computer Papers Report on Pascal (Box 96, Folder 1)
    - Computer Papers L10 Programming Binder, 1975 (Box 96, Folder 2)
    - Computer Papers Augmented Knowledge Workshop (Box 96, Folder 3)
    - Computer Papers Output Processor Binder, 1976 (Box 96, Folder 4)
    - Computer Papers Ideas, 1975 (Box 96, Folder 5)
    - Computer Papers Computer-Based Text System, 1978 (Box 96, Folder 6)
    - Computer Notes/Papers (Box 97, Folder 2)
    - Computer Notes/Papers (Box 98, Folder 1)
    - Augment Reference Pamphlets and Guides (Box 98, Folder 2)
    - Computer Notes/Papers (Box 99)
    - Computer Notes/Papers (Box 100)
    - Computer Notes/Papers (Box 101, Folder 1)
    - Project System Detailed Design, 1977 (Box 103, Folder 1)
    - SRI, October 1977 (Box 103, Folder 2)
    - SRI Query, February-April 1976 (Box 103, Folder 3)
    - NLS 8 .5 Sysgd, January 1976 (Box 103, Folder 4)
    - NLS 8.5 Csyngen to Inpfbk vol II, October 1976 (Box 103, Folder 5)
    - SRI, October 1976 (Box 103, Folder 6)
    - NLS 8.5 Pshelp to Verify vol IV, October 1976 (Box 103, Folder 7)
    - NLS Idexec to Psedit vol III, October 1976 (Box 103, Folder 8)
    - Circuits, Storage, Software, October 1976 (Box 103, Folder 9)
    - Computer Papers (Box 105, Folder 2)
    - Computer Papers Augment (Box 106, Folder 1)
    - Computer Papers Functions Guide (Box 106, Folder 2)
    - Computer Papers NLS-8 Glossary (Box 106, Folder 3)
    - Computer Papers Augment User Guides (Box 106, Folder 4)
    - Intro to Augment User Guides (Box 106, Folder 5)
    - Guides and Newsletters (Box 106, Folder 6)
    - NIC TNLS User Guide Draft, 1971 (Box 106, Folder 7)
    - User Guides (Box 106, Folder 8)
    - ONLS Preliminary Guide, 1971-1972 (Box 107, Folder 1)
    - Tymshare Reference Manual on Augment (Box 107, Folder 2)
    - Journal Documents, July-August 1973 (Box 107, Folder 3)
    - Courseware for NLS, July 1976 (Box 107, Folder 4)
    - Printed and On-line Documents vol I, 1981 (Box 107, Folder 5)
    - KEV DBMS February-October, 1979 (Box 107, Folder 6)
    - NLS Users Guide, 1968 (Box 107, Folder 12)
    - NLS-9 AdroMp-Ccalc January, 1978 (Box 107, Folder 13)
    - NLS-9 Colsrt-Fresntend 2 of 5 (Box 108, Folder 1)
    - NLS-9 Identsupport -NLS parse 3 of 5 (Box 108, Folder 2)
    - NLS-9 Optab-Psprograms 4 of 5 (Box 108, Folder 3)
    - NLS-9 Recfil-XL1TronTiMe 5 of 5 (Box 108, Folder 4)
    - NLS-9 Sysgd (Box 108, Folder 5)
    - Knowledge Workshop DevelopMent Guides, January 1976 (Box 108, Folder 6)
    - National Software Works Protocols, January 1975 (Box 108, Folder 7)
    - Computer Papers and Reports (Box 108, Folder 8)
    - Procedure Call Protocol, January 1975 (Box 108, Folder 9)
    - Augmentation Research Center, December 1974 (Box 108, Folder 10)
    - Computer Papers Document Productions and Control Systems, March 1977 (Box 109, Folder 1)
    - Computer Papers NLS-8 Glossary, July 1975 (Box 109, Folder 2)
  - Subseries 5.5 ARC Handbooks
    - ARC Handbook Sec I vol II User Documents TNLS Specific, September 1971 (Box 71, Folder 4)
    - ARC Handbook sect I vol IV User Documents Tenex (Box 71, Folder 5)
    - ARC Handbook sect I vol I User Documents NLS General (Box 71, Folder 6)
    - ARC Handbook sect I vol III User Documents DNLS Specific (Box 71, Folder 7)
    - ARC Handbook sect I vol V User Documents Dialog Support System (Box 71, Folder 8)
    - ARC Handbook sect I vol VI User Documents DEC, Output Processor (Box 71, Folder 9)
    - ARC Handbook sect I vol VII User Documents L10, Content Analyser, Sequence Generator, Sort (Box 71, Folder 10)
    - ARC Handbook sect II vol II System Documents ARC Software (Box 72, Folder 1)
    - ARC Handbook sect II vol I System Documents ARC Software (Box 72, Folder 2)
    - ARC Handbook Section R, vol I Miscellaneous (Box 81, Folder 2)
    - ARC Handbook Section 7, vol I Meetings (Box 81, Folder 3)
    - ARC Handbook Section 2, vol III System Documents Tenex, January-February 1972 (Box 81, Folder 4)
    - ARC Handbook Plasma Display Programming Manual (Box 81, Folder 5)
    - ARC Handbook Section 4, vol II Reports, 1967-1968 (Box 82, Folder 1)
    - ARC Handbook Section 4, vol III Report, 1969-1970 (Box 82, Folder 2)
    - ARC Handbook Section 4, vol IV Reports, 1970-1971 (Box 82, Folder 3)
    - ARC Handbook Section 5, vol I Think Pieces, 1971-1972 (Box 82, Folder 4)
    - ARC Handbook Section 6, vol I Procedures, 1971 (Box 82, Folder 5)
  - Subseries 5.6 Tymeshare Binders
    - Tymshare Binders CML Command Meta Language (Box 82, Folder 6)
    - Tymshare Binders Command Meta Language CML (Box 82, Folder 7)
    - Tymshare Binders Command Meta Language, 1977-1978 (Box 82, Folder 8)
    - Tymshare Binders Command Meta Language, February-December 1977 (Box 82, Folder 9)
    - Tymshare Binders Output Processor (Box 82, Folder 10)
    - Tymshare Binders TPS OS2000 Evaluation Team Manual (Box 82, Folder 11)
    - Tymshare Binders TOPS-20 (Box 90, Folder 2)
    - Tymshare Binders NLSBE #1, 1979 (Box 90, Folder 3)
    - Tymshare Binders FE #2, 1979 (Box 90, Folder 4)
    - Tymshare Binders NLSBE #2, 1979 (Box 90, Folder 5)
    - Tymshare Binders Output Processor, 1978 (Box 90, Folder 6)
    - Tymshare Binder GN Notes DCE Office, 1984 (Box 97, Folder 1)
    - Archive Tape Directory Listings vol I, March-[September?] 1974 (Box 101, Folder 3)
    - Archive Tape Directory Listings vol II, September 1974-March 1975 (Box 102, Folder 1)
    - Archive Tape Directory Listings vol III, February-May 1975 (Box 102, Folder 2)
    - Archive Tape Directory Listings vol. IV, April-June 1975 (Box 69, Folder 3)
    - Archive Tape Directory Listings vol. V, June-November 1975 (Box 69, Folder 4)
    - Archive Tape Directory Listings vol. VI, December 1975-March 1976 (Box 69, Folder 5)
    - Archive Tape Directory Listings vol. VII, March-July 1976 (Box 69, Folder 6)
    - Archive Tape Directory Listings vol. VIII, June-August 1976 (Box 69, Folder 7)
    - Archive Tape Directories vol. IX, 1976-January 1977 (Box 69, Folder 8)
    - Tymshare Binders General BS, December 1979-January 1980 (Box 107, Folder 7)
    - Tymshare Binders BS Subsystem Miscellaneous, October 1979-January 1980 (Box 107, Folder 8)
    - Tymshare Binders Revised Portions On-line Documents, 1982 (Box 107, Folder 9)
    - Tymshare Binders Revised Portions On-line Documents, 1981 (Box 107, Folder 10)
    - Tymshare Binders Printed and On-line Documents, 1982 (Box 107, Folder 11)
  - Subseries 5.7. Conferences
    - Book on the Conference for Computing Machinery, 1967 (Box 101, Folder 2)
    - SRI International Conference Binder (Box 76, Folder 6)
    - Computer Conference Proceedings, 1975 (Box 102, Folder 3)
    - Computer Conference Proceedings, 1968 (Box 102, Folder 4)
    - Computer Conference Proceedings, 1970 (Box 102, Folder 5)
    - Computer Conference Proceedings, (Spring) 1971 (Box 102, Folder 6)
    - Computer Conference Proceedings, (Fall) 1971 (Box 102, Folder 7)
    - AFIPS Conference Proceedings vol 35, 1969 (Box 103, Folder 10)
    - AFIPS Conference Proceedings vol 35, 1968 (Box 103, Folder 11)
    - AFIPS Conference Proceedings (Box 104, Folder 1)
    - Proceedings of the ASIS Annual Meeting vol 10, 1973 (Box 104, Folder 2)
    - AFIPS Conference Proceedings vol 26, 1964 (Box 104, Folder 3)
    - AFIPS Conference Proceedings vol 26, 1964 (Box 104, Folder 4)
    - AFIPS Conference Proceedings vol 27, 1965 (Box 104, Folder 5)
    - Proceedings of IFIP Congress, 1965 (Box 104, Folder 6)
    - AFIPS Conference Proceedings, 1965 (Box 104, Folder 7)
    - AFIPS Conference Proceedings, 1966 (Box 104, Folder 8)
    - AFIPS Conference Proceedings, 1967 (Box 104, Folder 9)
    - AFIPS Conference Proceedings, 1968 (Box 104, Folder 10)
    - Proceedings of the ASIS Annual Meeting vol 6, 1969 (Box 105, Folder 1)
- Series 6. Accession 2007-197
  - Files, 1988-1995 (Box 1 (2007-197))
  - Files, 1989-1991 (Box 2 (2007-197))
  - Files, 1992-1995 (Box 3 (2007-197))
  - Files, 1992-2003 (Box 4 (2007-197))
  - Files, 1994-1999 (Box 5 (2007-197))
  - Files, 1995-1997 (Box 6 (2007-197))
  - Files, 1997-1998 (Box 7 (2007-197))
  - Files, 1998-2005 (Box 8 (2007-197))
  - Files, 1999-2001 (Box 9 (2007-197))
  - Files, 2000-2003 (Box 10 (2007-197))
  - Files, 2000-2004 (Box 11 (2007-197))
  - Notebooks, 1985-1994 (Box 12 (2007-197))
  - Notebooks (Box 13 (2007-197))
  - Seminar/Workshop Files (Box 14 (2007-197))
  - Seminar 3,4,5,8; Slide/Foil Sets; Interop (Box 15 (2007-197))
  - Slide/Foil Sets (Box 16 (2007-197))
  - Slides & Talks, 1988-1990 (Box 17 (2007-197))
  - Book Binders and Pamphlets (Box 18 (2007-197))
  - Info Binders and Catalogs (Box 19 (2007-197))
  - Miscellaneous Publications/Articles (Box 20 (2007-197))
  - Miscellaneous Binders/Magazines (from various boxes) (Box 21 (2007-197))
  - Miscellaneous Oversize Binders (from various boxes) (Box 22 (2007-197))
  - Colloquium, Stanford University, March 2000 (cassettes); Seminar 6 (cassettes and VHS Tapes); Miscellaneous Tapes (Box 23 (2007-197))
  - Seminar 1, 2 & Metes Dial. (Cassettes and Transcriptions) (Box 24 (2007-197))
  - Seminar 3, 5, 6: Videotapes and cassettes; miscellaneous videotapes (Box 25 (2007-197))
  - Seminar 3: Videotapes; Miscellaneous videotapes (Box 26 (2007-197))
  - ¾” tapes, Computer disks, and Audiocassettes: Bootstrap, Presentations and Talks (Box 27 (2007-197))
  - Audiocassettes and Computer disks: Seminar 3 and miscellaneous (Box 28 (2007-197))
  - Bootstrap Binders: Seminar 3, 5 Transcriptions; Audio Log; Slide show log; Miscellaneous Bootstrap Papers (Box 29 (2007-197))
- Series 7. Accession 2007-269
  - XDOC Files (Box 1-9)
  - Files, Stakeholder Tapes, Slide Binders, 1990 (Box 10)
  - Seminar Binders, Slide Binders (Box 11)
  - Seminar 4,5,6,7,8; Info, 1990-1992 (Box 12)
  - Slides from 1980's, 1989 & 1990 Interview Tapes, Magazine Articles, 1990 File Folders, 1980s-1990s (Box 13)
  - Files, 1987-1990 (Box 14)
  - Oversized Materials (Box 15)
  - Seminar/Workshop Tapes [listing available], 1992-1998 (Box 16)
  - History Tapes [listing available] (Box 17-19)